Before I started pioneering,
開拓を始める前は 毎月
時間が入るか不安でした
I was really nervous that I wouldn’t be able
to get my time in every month.
It was a bit hard when I started pioneering
because I didn’t have a car.
車がなかったから
始めるのはちょっと大変でした
My boss,
he didn’t give me part-time work.
上司はパートを
認めてくれませんでした
I found it really hard
to balance schoolwork
学校と開拓の両立は大変でした
and pioneering
at the same time.
My biggest struggle was fear of man,
so that really hindered me
一番の障害は人への恐れでした
人と話すのが苦手だったからです
because I wasn’t very good
at talking to people.
Having a good routine was a struggle.
良い習慣を持つのに苦労しました
My brother and I are
the only ones in the truth.
真理にいるのは兄とわたしだけです
My family didn’t understand
なんで奉仕に行きたいのか
家族に理解してもらえませんでした
why we wanted to go preaching.
I didn’t think
that I’d make a good pioneer.
できるとは思えませんでした
I’ve had Type 1 diabetes
since I was five.
5歳の時からⅠ型の糖尿病なので—
So I was always worried
about whether or not
健康と開拓のバランスが取れるか
いつも心配でした
I could balance that health condition
with pioneering.
The challenges
don’t seem that big now,
今と比べて以前は
もっと問題が大きかったんです
but back at that time
they were a really big deal.
エホバの助けがすご過ぎです
But the coolest thing
was how Jehovah helped me.
Prayer to Jehovah
helped me overcome my fears.
祈って恐れを克服しました
My family was
a massive help from Jehovah.
家族はエホバからの強力な助けです
Because my dad was the one
who first encouraged me to pioneer,
開拓を最初に励ましてくれたのは父です
when I did start pioneering,
he promised that I would have
家族からのフルサポートを
約束してくれました
the full support of my family.
When I spoke to brothers and sisters
who spent their youth
若いときに全時間奉仕をした
兄弟姉妹と話すことが—
in the full-time service
that really helped me
大きな助けになりました
because it was really encouraging,
and it really motivated me
すごく力をもらって—
わたしも全時間奉仕を経験したい
っていう気持ちになりました
to want to make my own memories
and my own experiences
in the full-time service.
So there were
practical things I could do.
できることをしました
車がないから 歩くかバスに乗りました
I didn’t have a car;
I just walked or I caught the bus.
I had to work out
what my priorities were first.
優先順位を決めました
So I had to find out how many hours
would I have to go witnessing every week.
毎週 何時間奉仕すべきか考えました
それから 曜日ごとに いつ奉仕して
いつ学校に行くか計画を立てました
So then I just sat down
and I looked at every day
and planned out which days
I could go witnessing,
which days I had to go to school,
宿題とか研究する時間も
取れるようにしました
and also allocated time
so that I could do my homework and study.
Having a schedule
was really good
予定を立ててよかったです
because I could see it
all out in front of me,
やることを全部書きだしてみたら—
and I could see
that the hour requirement
要求時間を達成できるって分かって
無理って思わなくなりました
was actually attainable,
so that made it a lot less daunting.
I first set short-term goals of pioneering
in the special months of activity.
初めは 特別活動の月に
開拓をする短期的な目標を持ちました
Then I was able
to begin continuous auxiliary,
それから 連続で補助をして
最終的に正規開拓を始めました
and then eventually
I started regular pioneering.
One of the best things I did
to prepare myself for pioneering
すごくよかった開拓の準備は
補助開拓です
was to auxiliary pioneer beforehand.
開拓をしながら
直面するどんな困難も—
It really set me up
to be able to overcome
克服できるよう準備できました
any challenges
that I faced while I was pioneering.
I thought about Malachi 3:10.
マラキ 3章10節を考えました
I knew I trusted in Jehovah,
エホバを信頼していたけど
試みるいい機会でした
but this was my chance
to test him out.
I prayed,
put my trust in Jehovah,
祈って エホバを信頼し
申し込みました
and put my application in.
After my form
was in for pioneering,
開拓者になってしばらくして
ある兄弟が仕事をくれました
a brother, with time,
a brother called me and offered me work.
I had unemployment
for three months,
3か月仕事がなかったから大変でした
which wasn’t a good time.
でも その間に
エホバに注意を集中しました
But during that time,
I had Jehovah as my main focus.
エホバは支えてくださって
見捨てたりされませんでした
And so he supported me,
and he didn’t let me down.
Asking brothers and sisters to come
奉仕する人が少ない日に—
and work with me,
maybe on days that I knew
兄弟姉妹に一緒に働くよう
お願いしました
that I wouldn’t get as much support,
really helped.
すごく助けになりました
That helped me to organize
my hours a little bit more,
もっと時間を活用できるし
兄弟姉妹をよく知ることもできます
and also I’d get to know
my brothers and sisters more as well.
One of the greatest joys of pioneering
has been to pioneer with Mum.
すごく嬉しいのは
母と開拓ができることです
And we had the privilege of going
同じ開拓者学校に行けて
とてもよかったです
to the pioneer school together,
which was really special.
Psalm 16:8 reminds me
詩編 16編8節からエホバが
すぐそばにいてくださると分かります
that Jehovah is right beside me.
When I’m preaching,
it’s like Jehovah is holding my hand.
奉仕のとき
手を握ってくださっているみたいです
So with full-time service,
I love making Jehovah happy.
全時間奉仕をして
エホバを喜ばせたいです
与えられたものすべてを用いて
やっと少しお返しできます
With everything that he has given me,
I’m finally able to give something back.
Looking back
—pioneering—
振り返れば
開拓は今までで最善の決定です
it was the best decision
I’ve ever made.
It’s opened up
so many different avenues
エホバへのいろんな
奉仕の道が開かれます
of service to Jehovah,
また 全時間奉仕を続ける
真の願いを持つ助けにもなります
and it helped me also
to have that real desire
to want to stay
in full-time service.
Helping someone
on the road to everlasting life,
道行く人を永遠の命へ導くのは
最高です
it’s the best feeling ever;
and it’s really irreplaceable.
何にも代えられません
The only thing I can say,
勧めたいことはただ1つ—
“As a young person, start pioneering!”
“若いうちに 開拓奉仕！”